Now I'm going to demonstrate the double figure of eight hitch, loop; however you want to look at it.
Its really just a constrictor knot is all it is.
It?s used to tie around something, you know if you want to.
It?s kind of like a decorative or an ornamental knot.
So if you look down here, you can see I've got my line that I'm going to use.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to pull a little bit more out, because I'm going to need a lot of it.
This is going to be my working end over here.
I'm just going to loop, just a nice overhand loop over here on my working end.
I'm going to bring over here and I'm going to create an underhand loop, not like that, but like that.
So that they are kind of making this nice figure of eight as it comes around.
Now what I'm going to do is since my overhand loop, my initial loop I created, my working end.
Bring it back around and create another loop here, another just overhand loop.
And then I'm going to take my standing end that I have here and we'll bring it back around as well.
And we'll create another overhand loop as well on the other side.
Now, how this is going to be used is, I'm going to take my block of wood here, and I'm going to pick both of these pieces up and I'm going to slide my wood through.
And I'm just going to pull them through, like so.
And constrict these knots around this piece of wood.
Now I'll have to work it just a little bit, because there you go, pull.
My square piece of wood is going to create problems, but if this was a round piece like a broomstick or something, this would actually tighten up a lot tighter.
Now as you can see here, this is how your figure of eight loop should look.
Kind of weaving around, you know, weaving around through and of itself.
Create this nice constrictor type knot.